From the smallest beginnings come the greatest legends.
The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Peter Jackson.
Bilbo Baggins, a hobbit enjoying his quiet life, is swept into an epic quest by Gandalf the Grey
and thirteen dwarves who seek to reclaim their mountain home from Smaug, the dragon.
Bilbo Baggins, played by Martin Freeman.
Gandalf the Grey, played by Ian McKellen.
Thorin Oakenshield, played by Richard Armitage.
Bofur, played by James Nesbitt.
Balin, played by Ken Stott.
Radagast the Brown, played by Sylvester McCoy.
The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey is a 2012 epic high fantasy adventure film directed by Peter
Jackson from a screenplay by Fran Walsh, Philippa Boyens, Jackson, and Guillermo del Toro.
It is based on the 1937 novel The Hobbit by J.
The film is the first instalment in The Hobbit trilogy, acting as a
prequel to Jackson's The Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003).
The story is set in Middle-earth sixty years before the main events of The Lord of the Rings and
portions of the film are adapted from the appendices to Tolkien's The Return of the King.
An Unexpected Journey tells the tale of Bilbo Baggins (Martin Freeman), who is convinced by the wizard Gandalf (Ian McKellen) to accompany
thirteen Dwarves, led by Thorin Oakenshield (Richard Armitage), on a quest to reclaim the Lonely Mountain from the dragon Smaug.
The ensemble cast also includes Ken Stott, Cate Blanchett, Ian Holm, Christopher
Lee, Hugo Weaving, James Nesbitt, Elijah Wood, and Andy Serkis.
It features Sylvester McCoy, Barry Humphries, and Manu Bennett.
An Unexpected Journey premiered in Wellington on 28 November 2012, then released on 12
December in New Zealand and on 14 December in the United States, by Warner Bros.
It was almost nine years after the release of The Lord
of the Rings: The Return of the King.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $1.017 billion at the
box office, making it the fourth highest-grossing film of 2012.
The film received numerous accolades; at the 85th Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best
Production Design, Best Makeup and Hairstyling, and Best Visual Effects.
Two sequels, The Desolation of Smaug and The Battle of the Five
Armies followed in 2013 and 2014, respectively.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
elves, dwarf, magic, horseback riding.